A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Office of the Secretary of Public Safety, 2000-2006 (bulk 2002-2005)
Library of Virginia
- Series IX. Secretary's Correspondence, 2002-2006., Extent: 1.9 cu. ft. (Box 81-86)
  - I, 2004. (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - J, 2002-2005 (1 of 3). (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - J, 2002-2005 (2 of 3). (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - J, 2002-2005 (3 of 3). (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - K, 2002-2005 (1 of 3). (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - K, 2002-2005 (2 of 3). (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - K, 2002-2005 (3 of 3). (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - L, 2002-2005 (1 of 3). (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - L, 2002-2005 (2 of 3). (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - L, 2002-2005 (3 of 3). (Box 83, Folder 10)
  - M, 2002-2005 (1 of 9). (Box 83, Folder 11)
  - M, 2002-2005 (2 of 9). (Box 83, Folder 12)
  - M, 2002-2005 (3 of 9). (Box 83, Folder 13)
  - M, 2002-2005 (4 of 9). (Box 83, Folder 14)
  - M, 2002-2005 (5 of 9). (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - M, 2002-2005 (6 of 9). (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - M, 2002-2005 (7 of 9). (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - M, 2002-2005 (8 of 9). (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - M, 2002-2005 (9 of 9). (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - N, 2002-2006 (1 of 2). (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - N, 2002-2006 (2 of 2). (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - O, 2002-2005. (Box 84, Folder 8)
  - P, 2002-2005 (1 of 8). (Box 84, Folder 9)
  - P, 2002-2005 (2 of 8). (Box 84, Folder 10)
  - P, 2002-2005 (3 of 8). (Box 84, Folder 11)
  - P, 2002-2005 (4 of 8). (Box 84, Folder 12)
  - P, 2002-2005 (5 of 8). (Box 84, Folder 13)
  - P, 2002-2005 (6 of 8). (Box 84, Folder 14)
  - P, 2002-2005 (7 of 8). (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - P, 2002-2005 (8 of 8). (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Q, 2005. (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - R, 2002-2006 (1 of 3). (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - R, 2002-2006 (2 of 3). (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - R, 2002-2006 (3 of 3). (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - S, 2002-2006 (1 of 6). (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - S, 2002-2006 (2 of 6). (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - S, 2002-2006 (3 of 6). (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - S, 2002-2006 (4 of 6). (Box 85, Folder 10)
  - S, 2002-2006 (5 of 6). (Box 85, Folder 11)
  - S, 2002-2006 (6 of 6). (Box 85, Folder 12)
  - T, 2002-2005 (1 of 2). (Box 85, Folder 13)
  - T, 2002-2005 (2 of 2). (Box 85, Folder 14)
  - V, 2002-2006. (Box 85, Folder 15)
  - W, 2002-2005 (1 of 6). (Box 85, Folder 16)
  - W, 2002-2005 (2 of 6). (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - W, 2002-2005 (3 of 6). (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - W, 2002-2005 (4 of 6). (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - W, 2002-2005 (5 of 6). (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - W, 2002-2005 (6 of 6). (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Y, 2003. (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Z, 2004. (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Governor's Office for Substance Abuse Prevention, 2002 (1 of 2). (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Governor's Office for Substance Abuse Prevention, 2002 (2 of 2). (Box 86, Folder 9)
- Series X. Special Projects and Programs, 2000-2005., Extent: 4.7 cu. ft. (Box 87-100)
  Contains files pertaining to various projects and programs with which the Office of the Secretary of Public Safety was involved, both inside and outside of the Secretariat. The files contain reports, correspondence, minutes, notes, and other working documents. Information on a variety of Public Safety initiatives such as KIDSafe Virginia, the Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), and the Drug Offender Screening, Assessment and Treatment Initiative can be found in this series. Also included are files pertaining to various committees, task forces, and working groups devoted to public safety issues such as those devoted to offender forecasting, the Civil Commitment Working Group, the Sex Offender Task Force, and the Governor's Youth Public Safety Advisory Council (GYPSAC). A large number of files pertain to issues involving the Department of Corrections such as those devoted to offender population statistics, community corrections, and the inmate telephone system. Finally, this series also contains studies conducted by or on behalf of public safety agencies and groups, as well as several Public Safety-related reports. This series contains restricted information that has either been redacted or sealed. The material may include, but is not limited to, attorney-client privileged documents and proprietary information.
  The project/program files are arranged into the following alphabetically arranged categories: Alcoholic Beverage Control Board, Commonwealth's Attorneys' Services Council, Committees/Task Forces/Working Groups, Department of Corrections, Department of Criminal Justice Services, the Criminal Sentencing Commission, Initiatives, Department of Juvenile Justice, Legislation, Multi-Agency Projects, Department of State Police, and Studies/Reports. The individual files are arranged alphabetically or chronologically within.
  - Alcoholic Beverage Control Board, 2003-2005.
    - ABC Issues, 2004-2005. (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - ABC Issues, 2004-2005. (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - ABC Law Enforcement Merger with State Police, 2003. (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - ABC Law Enforcement Merger with State Police, 2003. (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - ABC Direct Wine Shipment Case, 2004-2005. (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - ABC Direct Wine Shipment Case, 2004-2005. (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - ABC Direct Wine Shipment Case, 2004-2005. (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - Commonwealth's Attorneys' Services Council, 2003.
    - CASC Merger with Dept. of Criminal Justice Services, 2003. (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - Committees/Task Forces/Working Groups, 2002-2005.
    - Appointment of Counsel for Delinquent Children Work Group, 2003. (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Appointment of Counsel for Delinquent Children Work Group, 2003. (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - Appointment of Counsel for Delinquent Children Work Group, 2003. (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - Civil Commitment Working Group, 2003-2004. (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - Civil Commitment Working Group, 2003-2004. (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - Civil Commitment Working Group, 2003-2004. (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Civil Commitment Working Group, 2003-2004. (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Civil Commitment Working Group, 2003-2004. (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Civil Commitment Working Group, 2003-2004. (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Court-Appointed Counsel Work Group, 2003. (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Funding Task Force of the Secure Commonwealth Panel, 2005. (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Funding Task Force of the Secure Commonwealth Panel, 2005. (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Governor's Youth Public Safety Advisory Council (GYPSAC), 2003-2004. (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Governor's Youth Public Safety Advisory Council (GYPSAC), 2003-2004. (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Governor's Youth Public Safety Advisory Council (GYPSAC), 2003-2004. (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - Policy Committee Meeting: Forecast of State and Local Adult and Juvenile Incarcerated Populations, 2002 August 22. (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - Policy Committee Meeting: Forecast of State and Local Adult and Juvenile Incarcerated Populations, 2003 August 6. (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - Policy Committee Meeting: Forecast of State and Local Adult and Juvenile Incarcerated Populations, 2003 August 6. (Box 88, Folder 13)
    - Policy Committee Meeting: Forecast of State and Local Adult and Juvenile Incarcerated Populations, 2003 August 20. (Box 88, Folder 14)
    - Policy Committee Meeting: Forecast of State and Local Adult and Juvenile Incarcerated Populations, 2003 September 15. (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Policy and Technical Advisory Committees for Offender Forecasting, 2002-2004. (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Policy and Technical Advisory Committees for Offender Forecasting, 2002-2004. (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Policy and Technical Advisory Committees for Offender Forecasting, 2002-2004. (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Policy and Technical Advisory Committees for Offender Forecasting, 2002-2004. (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Policy and Technical Advisory Committees for Offender Forecasting, 2002-2004. (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Sex Offender Task Force, 2005. (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Sex Offender Task Force, 2005. (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Subcommittee on Public Safety, 2005. (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - Subcommittee on Public Safety, 2005. (Box 89, Folder 10)
    - Special Task Force on Truck Safety, 2002. (Box 89, Folder 11)
    - Treatment Options for Offenders with Mental Illness or Substance Abuse Disorders (SJR 97/HJR 142) Interagency Work Group, 2002-2003. (Box 89, Folder 12)
    - Treatment Options for Offenders with Mental Illness or Substance Abuse Disorders (SJR 97/HJR 142) Interagency Work Group, 2002-2003. (Box 89, Folder 13)
    - Treatment Options for Offenders with Mental Illness or Substance Abuse Disorders (SJR 97/HJR 142) Interagency Work Group, 2002-2003. (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Treatment Options for Offenders with Mental Illness or Substance Abuse Disorders (SJR 97/HJR 142) Interagency Work Group, 2002-2003. (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Treatment Options for Offenders with Mental Illness or Substance Abuse Disorders (SJR 97/HJR 142) Interagency Work Group, 2002-2003. (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Treatment Options for Offenders with Mental Illness or Substance Abuse Disorders (SJR 97/HJR 142) Interagency Work Group, 2002-2003. (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Treatment Options for Offenders with Mental Illness or Substance Abuse Disorders (SJR 97/HJR 142) Interagency Work Group, 2002-2003. (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Corrections, Department of, 2000-2005.
    - Chesapeake Probation and Parole Office, 2002-2005. (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Chesapeake Probation and Parole Office, 2002-2005. (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Chesapeake Probation and Parole Office, 2002-2005. (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - Commissary Privatization, 2003. (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - Commissary Privatization, 2003. (Box 90, Folder 10)
    - Commissary Privatization, 2003. (Box 90, Folder 11)
    - "Community Corrections: A Balanced Approach," 2002-2003. (Box 90, Folder 12)
    - Community Corrections Funding, 2003. (Box 90, Folder 13)
    - Community Corrections Funding, 2003. (Box 90, Folder 14)
    - Containment Model for the Supervision of Sex Offenders in the Community, 2003. (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Fairfax Correctional Unit (Camp 40), 2002-2005. (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Fairfax Correctional Unit (Camp 40), 2002-2005. (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Inmate Telephone System, 2002. (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Inmate Telephone System, 2002. (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Inmate Telephone System, 2002. (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Inmate Telephone System, 2002. (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - Jails, 2005. (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - Jails, 2005. (Box 91, Folder 9)
    - Jails, 2005. (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Non-Violent Offenders and Good Conduct Time (petitions), 2003-2004. (Box 91, Folder 11)
    - Non-Violent Offenders and Good Conduct Time (petitions), 2003-2004. (Box 91, Folder 12)
    - Offender Re-Entry Programs, 2004. (Box 91, Folder 13)
    - Offender Re-Entry Programs, 2004. (Box 91, Folder 14)
    - Offender Re-Entry Programs, 2004. (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Offender Re-Entry Programs, 2004. (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Out-of-State Inmates, 2002-2004. (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Out-of-State Inmates, 2002-2004. (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - Out-of-State Inmates, 2002-2004. (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Out-of-State Inmates, 2002-2004. (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Out-of-State Inmates, 2002-2004. (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - Out-of-State Inmates, 2002-2004. (Box 92, Folder 8)
    - Out-of-State Inmates, 2002-2004. (Box 92, Folder 9)
    - Population Forecasts (Inmate) FY 2001-2010, 2000. (Box 92, Folder 10)
    - Population Forecasts (Inmate) FY 2002-2011, 2001. (Box 92, Folder 11)
    - Population Forecasts (Inmate) FY 2003-2012 c. 1, 2002. (Box 92, Folder 12)
    - Population Forecasts (Inmate) FY 2003-2012 c. 2, 2002. (Box 92, Folder 13)
    - Population Forecasts (Offender) FY 2004-2013, 2003. (Box 92, Folder 14)
    - Prisoner Re-Entry Meeting, 2003. (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Public-Private Education and Infrastructure Act, 2003. (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Criminal Justice Services, Department of, 2002-2005.
    - Drug Courts, 2002-2003. (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Drug Courts, 2002-2003. (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - Pre-Release and Post Incarceration Services (PAPIS), 2002-2005. (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Private Crime Prevention Specialist Certification Program, 2003. (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - Sight and Sound Separation Under the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Act Presentation, 2003. (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Criminal Sentencing Commission, 2002-2003.
    - Alternative Sentencing and Technical Violators, 2002-2003. (Box 93, Folder 8)
    - Alternative Sentencing and Technical Violators, 2002-2003. (Box 93, Folder 9)
    - Alternative Sentencing and Technical Violators, 2002-2003. (Box 93, Folder 10)
    - Alternative Sentencing and Technical Violators, 2002-2003. (Box 93, Folder 11)
    - Alternative Sentencing and Technical Violators, 2002-2003. (Box 93, Folder 12)
    - Offender Risk Assessment in Virginia, 2002. (Box 93, Folder 13)
  - Initiatives, 2002-2005.
    - Drug Offender Screening, Assessment and Treatment Initiative, 2002-2003. (Box 93, Folder 14)
    - Drug Offender Screening, Assessment and Treatment Initiative, 2002-2003. (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Drug Offender Screening, Assessment and Treatment Initiative, 2002-2003. (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - Drug Offender Screening, Assessment and Treatment Initiative, 2002-2003. (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - Drug Offender Screening, Assessment and Treatment Initiative, 2002-2003. (Box 94, Folder 4)
    - Drug Offender Screening, Assessment and Treatment Initiative, 2002-2003. (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Drug Offender Screening, Assessment and Treatment Initiative, 2002-2003. (Box 94, Folder 6)
    - Drug Offender Screening, Assessment and Treatment Initiative, 2002-2003. (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - Drug Offender Screening, Assessment and Treatment Initiative, 2002-2003. (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - Drug Offender Screening, Assessment and Treatment Initiative, 2002-2003. (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - Drug Offender Screening, Assessment and Treatment Initiative Implementation Evaluation, 2002-2003. (Box 94, Folder 10)
    - KIDSafe Virginia, 2002-2004. (Box 94, Folder 11)
    - KIDSafe Virginia, 2002-2004. (Box 94, Folder 12)
    - KIDSafe Virginia, 2002-2004. (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Project Salva Ninos (anti-gang), 2004. (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Project Salva Ninos (anti-gang), 2004. (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Project Salva Ninos (anti-gang), 2005. (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Protect and Respect, 2003-2004. (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Protect and Respect, 2003-2004. (Box 95, Folder 6)
    - Students Mentoring for After School Hope (SMASH), 2005. (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - Students Mentoring for After School Hope (SMASH), 2005. (Box 95, Folder 8)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2002. (Box 95, Folder 9)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2002. (Box 95, Folder 10)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2003. (Box 95, Folder 11)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2003. (Box 95, Folder 12)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2003. (Box 95, Folder 13)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2004. (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2004. (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2004. (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2004. (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2004. (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2004. (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2004. (Box 96, Folder 7)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2004. (Box 96, Folder 8)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2004. (Box 96, Folder 9)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2004. (Box 96, Folder 10)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2005. (Box 96, Folder 11)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2005. (Box 96, Folder 12)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2005. (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS) Monthly Reports, 2004. (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS) Monthly Reports, 2005 January-July. (Box 97, Folder 3)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS) Monthly Reports, 2005 August-November. (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS)-- Tower in King William County, 2005. (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - Juvenile Justice, Department of, 2002-2005.
    - Camp Pendleton Property (Virginia Beach), 2002. (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - Culpeper Juvenile Correctional Center Utilization Study, 2002-2005. (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - Culpeper Juvenile Correctional Center Utilization Study, 2002-2005. (Box 97, Folder 8)
    - Culpeper Juvenile Correctional Center Utilization Study, 2002-2005. (Box 97, Folder 9)
    - Culpeper Juvenile Correctional Center Utilization Study, 2002-2005. (Box 97, Folder 10)
    - Culpeper Juvenile Correctional Center Utilization Study, 2002-2005. (Box 97, Folder 11)
    - Culpeper Juvenile Correctional Center Utilization Study, 2002-2005. (Box 97, Folder 12)
    - Data Resource Guide FY 2003, 2004. (Box 97, Folder 13)
  - Legislation, 2002-2003.
    - Governor's Office for Substance Abuse Prevention (GOSAP) Projects--Bill Signing, 2003. (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Legislation, 2003. (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Protection of Information in Court Records (HJR 89), 2002. (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - Sexually Violent Predator Amendment, 2002-2003. (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - Multi-Agency Projects, 2003-2005.
    - Iraq Military Conflict Response, 2003. (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - Iraq Military Conflict Response, 2003. (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Iraq Military Conflict Response, 2003. (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Fusion Center, 2004-2005. (Box 98, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Fusion Center, 2004-2005. (Box 98, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Fusion Center, 2004-2005. (Box 98, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Fusion Center, 2004-2005. (Box 98, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Fusion Center, 2004-2005. (Box 98, Folder 12)
    - Virginia Fusion Center, 2004-2005. (Box 98, Folder 13)
  - State Police, 2005.
    - National Sex Offender Public Registry, 2005. (Box 98, Folder 14)
    - Southwest Virginia Methamphetamine Awareness Seminar, 2005. (Box 98, Folder 15)
    - Southwest Virginia Methamphetamine Awareness Seminar, 2005. (Box 98, Folder 16)
    - Southwest Virginia Methamphetamine Awareness Seminar, 2005. (Box 98, Folder 17)
  - Studies and Reports, 2002-2005.
    - Agency Studies (miscellaneous), 2002. (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Agency Studies (miscellaneous), 2003. (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - Agency Studies (miscellaneous), 2003. (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - Agency Studies (miscellaneous), 2004. (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Agency Studies (miscellaneous), 2004. (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Agency Studies (miscellaneous), 2005. (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - Civil Commitment Procedures Report, 2003. (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - Evaluation of Red Light Camera Enforcement in Virginia, 2004. (Box 99, Folder 8)
    - Juvenile Correctional Center Utilization Report, 2004. (Box 99, Folder 9)
    - Manpower Augmentation Study (State Police), 2005. (Box 99, Folder 10)
    - Operational Status Report (Secretariat), 2003. (Box 99, Folder 11)
    - Options for Future Utilization of Culpeper Juvenile Correctional Center, 2003. (Box 99, Folder 12)
    - Plan to Merge the Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control's Bureau of Law Enforcement with the Department of State Police, 2003. (Box 99, Folder 13)
    - Report on the Feasibility of Public-Private Partnerships to Finance Required Facilities for the Departments of Corrections, Juvenile Justice, Military Affairs, and State Police, 2003. (Box 99, Folder 14)
    - Report on the Status and Effectiveness of Offender Drug Screening, Assessment and Treatment, 2004. (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Review of the Patrol Staffing Formula (State Police), 2003. (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - Study on Alternative Training Delivery Methods for Criminal Justice Officers, 2004. (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Study on Locating and Implementing a Treatment Program for Civil Commitment of Sexually Violent Predators, 2003. (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - Study on Regional Criminal Justice Training Academy Fees: Training Services Provided to Non-Governmental Agencies or Organizations, 2004. (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - Study Workplan, 2002. (Box 100, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Fire Service Needs Assessment, Supplement I., 2004. (Box 100, Folder 7)
- Series XI. Speeches, 2002-2005., Extent: .35 cu. ft. (Box 101)
  Contains print-outs of speeches given by Secretary of Public Safety John Marshall. Secretary Marshall spoke at a variety of events, most notably police academy graduations, drug court graduations, public safety conferences, and memorial services.
  The speeches are arranged by year, and alphabetically within each year. The speeches are alphabetized either by the title of the speech, by the title of the event, or by the title of the association or group hosting the event.
  - Speeches, 2002.
    - Albemarle County Police Department Memorial Service speech, 2002 May 13. (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Central Shenandoah Criminal Justice Training Academy dedication ceremony speech, 2002 April 10. (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Chesterfield County PD/SO, VSP Division 1 Area 6 Police Memorial Program speech, 2002 May 14. (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Commonwealth Challenge graduation speech, 2002 December 21. (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Criminal Justice Services Community Partnerships Conference speech, 2002 April 29. (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Central Virginia Criminal Justice Academy graduation speech, 2002 June 19. (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - "Eyes on Richmond" Series speech, 2002 September 13. (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Manassas Park High School graduation speech, 2002 June 16. (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Norfolk Police Department Memorial Program speech, 2002 May 13. (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Rappahannock Regional Criminal Justice Academy graduation speech, 2002 May 17. (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - Richmond Police Department Memorial Service speech, 2002 May 16. (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Association of Chiefs of Police Annual Conference Banquet speech, 2002 August 8. (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Association of Regional Jails 4th Annual Training Conference speech, 2002 April 13. (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Correctional Association speech, 2002 September 17. (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - Virginia State Police Memorial Program speech, 2002 May 15. (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - Virginia State Police 6th Annual Volunteer Recognition Ceremony speech, 2002 April 25. (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - Speeches, 2003.
    - Ashland Police Department 20th Annual Awards Banquet, 2003 May 12. (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - Black History Month Program remarks, 2003 February 20. (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - Crime Victims' Rights Week Commemoration speech, 2003 April 8. (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - Criminal Justice Services Community Partnerships Conference speech, 2003 April 29. (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - Fairfax County Fire and Rescue Department graduation speech, 2003 June 27. (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - GYPSAC Speakout session speech (Richmond), 2003 July 29. (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - GYPSAC Speakout session speech (Arlington), 2003 November 10. (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - Herring, Officer Sheila funeral remarks, 2003 January. (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - Law Enforcement Memorial Program remarks, 2003 May 5. (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - MADD Smith Mountain Lake Regional Chapter 10th Annual Law Enforcement Awards Dinner speech, 2003 May 20. (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - Professional Investigators and Security Association Conference speech, 2003 March 7. (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - "Protect and Respect" speech, 2003 May 22. (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - Public Safety Awards Ceremony speech, 2003 May 27. (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - Rappahannock Regional Criminal Justice Academy graduation, 2003 May 8. (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - Richmond Adult Treatment Court speech, 2003 January 31. (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - Richmond Police Department graduation speech, 2003 March 14. (Box 101, Folder 5)